

Ruthvik MR

Designation: Software Engineer

Portfolio: GitHub Profile Linkedin Profile

PROFILE

Software engineer with 2 years of experience as a frontend developer.

Experience with the tools like gitLab, azure Devops, JIRA.

Experienced with scrum based delivery.

Passionate to work on technically challenging projects.

Hardworking, disciplined, punctual, self-confident and always willing to learn.

Skills: Angular, React JS, Javascript

Developer Tools: Visual Studio Code, GitHub, Azure devops

Database: MongoDB

Areas of Interest: React Native, Dockers and kubernetes

WORK EXPERIENCE

•Knowledge Lens: A Rockwell Automation Company

June 1 2022 - Present

Bengaluru

Software Engineer

- FT Data Mosaix (August 2023 Present) I'm involved in building user interfaces, developing Angular components, managing state and data, implementing routing, testing, visualization i.e Apache EChart's, debugging, optimizing performance, and collaborating using version control systems and adding value to the product.
- Emerson-PKM (January 2023 to July 2023) Developed new feature for the product by building new UI screens, Collaborated closely with backend developers to integrate APIs and with UX designers to ensure the UI met all specifications and branding guidelines, managing state and data, debugging, optimizing performance and collaborating with role access system permissions
- Audit Lens (September 2022 December 2022) Developed and maintained user-facing features using React.js and Redux, ensuring a seamless and interactive user experience

•Knowledge Lens: A Rockwell Automation Company

January 17 2022 - May 31 2022

Intern

Bengaluru

- Training Solid understanding of JavaScript, including ES6+ syntax, closures, async programming.
- Onboarding App (March 2022 May 2022) Designed and built user interface screens from the scratch with React-Bootstrap, and integrated them with the fast API.

PERSONAL PROJECTS (PLAY STORE)

•Wallet 2021

Wallet, a Android Mobile Application

- Tools & technologies used: Android Studio, Java
- An android java application, where we can store our personal details such as UPI and Card Details.It also has separate gallery to store the Document Photos such as DL,PAN number etc..

•Portfolio 2024

 $Web\ Application$

- Tools & technologies used: VS Code, React JS, Bootstrap, antd
- Have Implemented routing, managing data using props, JSON driven, collaborating using version control, monitored auto deployment to firebase on PR merge

EDUCATION

Sankalpa

•Amrita School of Arts and Sciences

2017 - 2022 CGPA : 6.9

Master of Computer Applications (MCA), Amrita Vishwa Vidyapeetham, karnataka

2017

+12th, Karnataka Board of the Pre-university Education, Karnataka

Percentage: 71.16%

•S T Thomas High School

2015

10th ,Karnataka Board Of Secondary Education, Karnataka

Percentage: 77.60%

AWARDS AND RECOGNITION

•Star of the Month